翻译：小布拿拿      Tiogy      红豆包      斯人
翻译&校对&总监：Iz
后期：斯人     时间轴：深夏桃子
《开心汉堡店》第五季第六集
除虫害公司
老鲍勃汉堡  三十年前
鲍勃  多谢煎我啊
Hey, Bob. Thanks for cooking me.
你铲子用得真是得心应手
You're pretty good with that spatula;
-你多大了  -十四岁
- How old are you? - 14.
天才啊
You're like a prodigy.
我的确很棒
Yeah, I'm pretty good, I guess.
好痒痒  我喜欢
That tickles, I like it.
汉堡好了  亨利
Here you go, Henry.
这是什么
What's this?
我点的是老样子啊
I ordered the usual.
我老爸去检查前列腺
Since Pop's getting his prostate checked,
今天就由我来掌勺
and I'm manning the grill,
我寻思着  为什么不来点特别的呢
I thought, why not try the unusual?
亨利  我向你介绍
Henry, I present to you
"宝贝开我的车吧"汉堡[披头士歌名]
"Baby You Can Chive My Car Burger."
酸奶油  洋葱  四周是煎过的腌黄瓜
Sour cream, chives, and little fried pickle wheels
做车轮  做成一辆汽车的样子
on the sides that make it look like a car.
你知道他是成年人吧
You know he's a grown man, right?
某人今天工作得很开心嘛
Someone's having fun at work today.
是的  非常开心
Yep, a lot.
我脑中冒出了很多新奇的点子
I came up with a bunch of ideas for specials.
克里"酥"蒂・布林克利汉堡
The Crispy Brinkley Burger,
克里斯蒂・布林克利  美国模特
理查德・西门[减肥教练]汉堡
the Richard Per-Simmons Burger,
贪婪干酪汉堡
the Greed is Gouda Burger...
－别激动  －得了  得了
－ Easy, easy, whew. － Okay, okay.
抱歉  我太兴奋了
Sorry, I got excited.
我只是对这个很热心
I-I'm just passionate.
原来前列腺检查就是这样啊
So that's what a prostate exam is.
你们知道是什么样吗
Did you guys know what it was?
我觉得还是保留点神秘感更好
I think it's more fun if it's a surprise.
老鲍勃  看看小鲍勃做的汉堡
Hey, Big Bob, look what Little Bob made.
小鲍  这是啥
Junior, what is this?
这是"宝贝开我的车吧"汉堡
It's a "Baby You Can Chive My Car Burger."
啥啥啥汉堡
A what you can what my what burger?
亨利  这是你点的吗  你点了什么
Henry, did you order this? What'd you order?
老样子  但这个看起来也可以
The usual, but this looks okay.
我喜欢汽车
I-I like cars.
吃吃看  亨利  你也许会喜欢
Try it, Henry, y-you might like it.
别告诉他该吃什么  小鲍勃
Don't tell him what to eat, Junior.
他没点那个  他爱吃金枪鱼三明治
He didn't order that, he's a tuna melt man...
看看他
look at him.
我来尝尝吧  我吃片轮子
I-I'll take a bite. I'll eat the wheel.
嘿嘿嘿
Hey, hey, hey, hey,
我是我的汉堡汽车  起开
it's my burger-car. Get off.
谁也别吃
It's nobody's burger-car.
我去做金枪鱼三明治
We'll make you a tuna melt.
都给我别吵了
Just everybody shush!
我再也不去检查前列腺了
That's the last time I get my prostate checked.
现在
赶紧的  泰迪
Wrap it up, Teddy.
我们得关门了
We got to close up.
我们要去参加老鲍勃的平安夜派对
We're going to Big Bob's Christmas Eve party.
泰迪  慢点吃
Teddy, eat slower.
有点太慢了
Actually, that's too slow.
亲爱的圣诞老人  今年
Dear Lord Santa, this year,
请赐我一个日历
please bless me with a calendar
上面要有澳大利亚消防员怀抱小狗的生活照
of Australian firefighters holding puppies in casual settings.
赐我一头卷发吧
And bless me with a perm.
人只活一次  为何不在头上找点乐子呢
You only live once; Why not have a little fun up top?
圣诞老人  请赐我一份
And, Santa, bless me
你们公司的实习工作
with an internship at your company.
最好的是在飞天动物部
Preferably something in the flying animal
或是"擅闯民宅"部  谢谢
or breaking and entering department, thank you.
孩子们  虽然今天是圣诞前夜
Kids, I know it's Christmas Eve
但没有人向圣诞老人祈祷好吗
but I don't think you pray to Santa.
圣诞老人  打倒他
Lord Santa, strike him down!
这话提醒我了
That reminds me.
我今晚应该去参加午夜弥撒
I'm supposed to go to midnight mass tonight.
或者午夜篮球
Either that or midnight basketball.
但我把短裤落车里了
I've got my shorts in the truck.
你们觉得我该怎么办
What do you think I should do?
把二者结合起来  弥撒球
Combine them... mass-ketball!
好了  咱们走吧
All right, let's go.
老鲍勃的平安夜派对  我们来啦
Big Bob's Christmas party, here we come.
我不想去
I don't want to go.
再说了  如果从头到尾我爸只是
Plus, is it a party if my dad just works the whole time
做汉堡跟收钱  那还是派对吗
and charges people?
那就是经营餐厅好吗
Isn't that just being a restaurant?
这是圣诞节  他每年都请我们  必须去
It's Christmas, he invites us every year, we're going.
但我们两年前才去过
But we just went two years ago.
-那是七年前  -你确定吗
- That was seven years ago. - You sure?
我记得  那时我还在喝奶呢
I remember. I was still breast-feeding.
-不  你没有  -又没喝你的
- No, you weren't. - Not with you.
得  我们去
Fine, we'll go,
但我们得遵守15分钟定律
but we're sticking to the 15-minute rule.
什么  你说啥
What? What are you talking about?
我只能
It-It's that I can only be
和我老爸相处15分钟
around my dad for 15 minutes.
在我彻底抓狂之前  就得离开
Then I have to leave before I completely lose it.
开心汉堡店盛大开业
祝好运
Well, good luck.
我看这餐馆也就开三个月
I give it three months.
我要进去了
I'm gonna go inside.
我在你这个年龄时可比你瘦多了
You're a lot fatter than I was at your age.
得走了
Gotta go.
好可爱的孩子
cute kid.
你给他起名叫吉恩吗
So you named him Gene, huh?
是不是来不及换名字了
Is it too late to change that?
我得走了
I'm gonna leave now.
-但这是你家  -没关系
- But this is your house. - That's okay.
对  现在老爸每次只能和爷爷呆15分钟
Yep, so now Dad only sees Grandpa in 15-minute intervals.
很像闪电约会  只不过对象是你老爸
It's like speed dating but with your dad.
父子矛盾  我们都经历过
Hey, father issues... we all got 'em.
我也母子矛盾
I've got mother issues, too.
甚至还有表妹矛盾
I've even got cousin issues.
和金发美女表妹的矛盾
Beautiful blonde cousin issues.
－什么  －别管你那15分钟定律了
－ What? － Oh, forget your 15-minute rule.
今晚是你和老爷子
Tonight's the night you and your dad
终于重修合好的时刻
finally patch everything up.
因为 圣诞节的魔力
Because of Christmas magic
*圣诞魔力*
*Christmas magic *
-每年的这一时刻  -好了  停
- This time of year - Okay, stop, stop.
-这一年的此时  -停  停  泰迪
- This time of year - Stop, stop, Teddy.
*那些又冷又饿的人*
*And all the cold hungry people *
*在大街上奄奄一息*
*They're dying in the streets *
*而我们一家人今晚会暖洋洋的*
*Me and my family will be warm tonight*
行了  琳
Okay, Lin.
不管怎样  我们几个和爷爷相处得蛮好
Anyway, the rest of us get along great with Pop Pop.
我很欣赏他关于是谁在搞垮美国的观点
I enjoy his opinions on what's ruining America.
你知道你该干嘛吗
You know what you should do?
你该管他要五美金
You should ask him for $5.
他会给你的  现金
He'll give it to you... in cash.
好吧  很好  很好
Okay, fine, fine.
我们都去爷爷家
We're... w-we'll go to Grandpa's.
但我们只去呆15分钟
But we're only going for 15 minutes.
泰迪  在教堂玩开心  或蓝球打开心
Teddy, have fun at church. Or basketball.
不管干哪个我都要穿短裤
Either way, I'm wearing shorts.
*又到了圣诞节*
*Oh, it's Christmastime again...
你们给爸妈买礼物了吗
Guys, guys, did you get presents for Mom and Dad?
我买了老妈想要的嘻哈瑜伽视频
I got Mom that hip-hop yoga video she wanted.
我也出了钱的
I went in on it.
蒂娜  我欠你多少
Tina, how much do I owe you?
开玩笑的  还是你来吧
Just kidding, it's on you.
很好  这个算我们仨的
Great, that'll be from all of us.
我们给老爸买了什么  蒂娜
So what did we get Dad, Tina?
我什么都没给他买
I didn't get him anything.
干得漂亮呀  T
Oh, way to go, T.
我和吉恩那么用心
Gene and I are pulling our weight.
没错  蒂娜
Yeah, Tina.
对不起嘛  我最近太忙了
Sorry, it's just been a crazy season.
"抱歉"能给老爸当礼物么
Well, we can't put "Sorry" Under the tree, can we?
我口袋里有什么就送他什么好了
We'll just give him whatever's in my pocket.
巧克力葡萄干
A chocolate-covered raisin.
巧克力吃了  就葡萄干好了
Scratch that. A raisin.
我擦  每年都这样
Crap, this happens every year.
只好等到了爷爷那儿给他准备一份礼物了
Well, we're gonna have to make him a gift at Grandpa's.
到了
There it is.
我们餐厅的老爸
Our restaurant's dad.
老鲍勃汉堡
看谁来啦
Hey, look who's here.
嗨  皮特
Hey, Pete.
鲍勃一家  圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas, Bob and family.
圣诞快乐  皮特
Merry Christmas, Pete!
你们太久没来
You haven't been here in so long,
我都长出大白胡子了
I grew a big white beard.
开个玩笑  这是圣诞老人的胡子
Just kidding, it's a Santa beard.
我自己的胡子长这样
This is my real beard.
继续脱
Keep going!
俄罗斯套胡
Russian nesting beards!
你的酒吧怎么样啦
How's your bar?
皮特是隔壁酒吧的主人  还记得吗
Pete owns the bar next door, remember?
还那么基吗  生意还旺吗
Is it still gay, still going strong?
更基更旺  这是我们的口号
Stronger and gayer than ever. That's our motto.
*更基更旺*
*Stronger and gayer than ever! *
听我为你做了首广告歌
I just wrote a jingle for you.
她今晚"歌兴"很高
She's pretty "Singy" Tonight.
*对*
*Yeah. *
老鲍勃在后面
Hey, Big Bob's in the back,
该去给他个拥抱了吧
and I think it's hug o'clock.
-对吧  孩子们  -好的
- Kids? - I get it.
我们来啦  爷爷
We're coming for you, Pop Pop.
慢用
Here you go.
老鲍勃  圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas, Big Bob.
琳达  孩子们
Linda, kids.
你好像每年都在变小
Boy, you get smaller every year.
以后我就不叫你老鲍勃
When do I stop calling you Big Bob
改叫缩水鲍勃了
and start calling you Old Wrinkly Shriveled-Up Bob?
够了  够了
All right, all right.
抱歉
Sorry.
我的孙儿们最近怎么样啦
And how are my grandkids doing?
我有个麻烦
I got problems,
但是五块钱就能解决
but nothing five dollars wouldn't fix.
爷爷  你看起来真年轻
Grandpa, you don't look a day over grandpa age.
-你太可爱了  蒂娜  -谢谢
- You're a doll, Tina. - Thank you.
看我有什么
Hey, look what I got here.
你最喜欢哪位总统[指钞票上的头像]
Who's your favorite president?
比尔・普曼[美剧《总统一家》演员]
Bill Pullman!
今日  我们为自由而战
"Today we fight for our independence!"
拿着
Here you go.
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas.
谢谢爷爷  爷爷
Thanks, Gramps. Hey, listen.
我们急需手工工具
We have an arts and crafts emergency.
需要胶水  纸  还有意面
We need glue, we need paper, we need pasta.
真的非常需要
We need it, like, yesterday.
你有多少种大小不同的塑料假眼睛
How many sizes of googly-eyes do you have?
一种都没有
I don't really have any of that.
但是地下室有很多废品
But I've got a bunch of crap down in the basement
你们想去瞅瞅吗
if you kids want to take a look.
他人之弃物  就是老爸的礼物
One man's trash is another man's present for their father.
-儿子  -还好吗
- Hey, Junior. - How are things?
我的帮厨今天请假了
My prep guy's gone tonight.
他女儿要生小孩  他去医院了
Went to the hospital 'cause his daughter's having a baby.
人真是自私啊
People can be pretty selfish, I guess.
坏小孩
Jerk baby.
琳达
Linda.
等等
h-hold on here.
鲍鲍  气氛不错嘛
Bobby, this is going well.
等再过十四分半再下结论吧
Yeah, check back with me in 14-and-a-half minutes.
圣诞魔力
Christmas magic.
-别再说这个了  -我偏要说
- Stop saying that. - No, I don't want to.
你今晚好忙啊  老鲍勃
You sure look slammed tonight, Big Bob.
不然找个人帮帮你
Seems like you could use a hand.
-要是正好有个人  -琳  别这样
- If only there was someone here... - Lin, no.
-对厨房又熟悉  -够了
- Who knew their way around the kitchen... - Stop.
还熟悉菜单
They knew the menu...
-琳  不要  -知道芝士要去哪儿拿
- Lin, no. - Where to get the cheese...
-不  -知道要放哪里
- No. Knew where that goes.
-够了  -进出自如
- Stop. - They knew their way around.
-够了  -了如指掌
- Stop it. - Like the back of their hand.
就像从小在这长大一样
Like they were raised here.
-别  我不  -我也觉得他不...
- No, no. I-I don't. - Yeah, I doubt he'd...
鲍勃可以帮忙
Bob could help cook.
不  我才不要
No, I-I don't...
我会脱不了身的
I'll get trapped in there...
15分钟定律
15-minute rule.
-那是你爸爸  -别说了
- It's you father... - Stop it.
-那是你爸爸  -住嘴
- It's your father. - Shut up.
好啦
All right!
你们爷俩  合作愉快
You two bond, have fun!
20年前
好了
Okay, this is it.
我要给小鲍圣诞礼物了
I'm gonna give Little Bob his Christmas gift.
大家准备好了吗
Everybody ready?
小鲍
Bob Junior!
怎么了
Wh-What's going on?
鲍鲍  你打出生就在这里工作
Bobby, you've been working here your whole life.
你一定一直在等这一天
And I'm sure you've been waiting for this day.
什么情况
W-What are you doing?
从这一刻开始
From this point forward,
老鲍勃汉堡店正式更名为
Big Bob's Diner will officially be called...
爸  不要
Oh, Dad, don't.
父与子汉堡
...Bob and Son's.
太好了
All right!
父与子汉堡
新菜单  以及
The new menus. And...
好吧  这个本来是要写"子"的
Okay, that's gonna say "Son's."
还没做完  不过很棒  不是吗
It's not done yet, but it's great, huh?
是我表弟喷的
My cousin's painting it.
他动作慢  一天只能画一个字母
He's slow, he can only do about a letter a day,
但他拼写能力超强
but he can spell like a son of a bitch.
超强
Like a son of a bitch.
来  伙伴
Come here, partner.
好啦  想当我的伙伴吗
Come on, want to be partners, or what?
不想
No?
不用谢
You're welcome.
我...  等等  你说什么
I think... Wait, what'd you just say?
我说不想
I said no.
我不可能做你的搭档
I could never be partners with you.
没人能和你共事
You're impossible to work with.
-什么  -小鲍勃  冷静点
- What? - Oh, boy. Easy, Little Bob.
我想换菜单
I want to change the menu,
你从来都不想
a-and you never want to change the menu.
你总是批评这批评那
And you're so critical.
每次连我拿个锅铲
I can't even lift a spatula without
你都要说我拿错
you saying I'm doing it wrong.
因为你就是拿错了
'Cause you're doing it wrong!
不然让锅铲决定
L-Let's let the spatula decide.
你们叫它的名字
You both call it,
看它跟谁
a-and we'll see who it goes to.
我想要在厨房里一展身手
I want to express myself in the kitchen!
但每次一这么说  他就发出怪声
And when I say that, he makes this weird sound!
就是这个声音
That sound!
这算什么
What is that?!
你是认真的吗
You're gonna do this?
非得现在吗  在所有人面前吗
Right now? In front of everybody?
那行  滚出去
You know what? Get out!
带着你那搞笑汉堡滚吧
Take your jokey burger specials and go!
行  你刚给了我新的汉堡灵感
Fine! You just gave me a new burger idea.
"我要自己发芽"汉堡
The I'm Sproutta Here Burger.
配豆芽菜
Comes with sprouts.
不  换一个
not that but something else.
有个更好的了
I thought of a better one!
"我在别处
The "I'd Be Cheddar Off
会干得更好"汉堡
Literally Anywhere But Here Burger!"
配干酪  算了
Comes with aged cheddar... forget it!
算了  去他妈的圣诞快乐
Forget it! Merry freaking Christmas!
圣诞快乐  小鲍勃
Merry Christmas, Little Bob!
琳  计划不是这样的
Lin, this was not the plan.
让我和我爸一起做汉堡不在计划内
Me cooking with my father at the party was not the plan.
计划已经被彻底打乱了
We are radically off plan.
鲍勃  冷静点  听我说
Bob, calm down. Listen to me.
这对你俩是个
This is a great opportunity for you two
化敌为友的好机会
to turn your bad blood to glad blood.
来  鲍勃  来点圣诞魔法吧
Here, Bob, have some Christmas magic, eh?
等等  圣诞魔法就是红酒吗
Wait, Christmas magic is wine?
你觉得是什么就是什么
It's whatever you want it to be.
可以是雪  圣诞老人  啤酒
It can be snow or Santa or beer
琴酒  朗姆酒  杜松子酒
or gin or rum or schnapps.
我  我懂了
I-I get it.
听着  我已经和他共处五分钟了
Listen, I've been with him for five minutes,
我现在倒计时十分钟
so I'm setting this timer for ten minutes,
到时间就走
and then I'm leaving.
那我把这时间设到永远
Well, I'm setting this timer to forever.
因为这代表
'Cause that's how long
你和你爸会爱对方多久
you and your father are gonna love each other.
多谈谈心  鲍勃  别谈你的乳头
Talking about your heart, Bob, not your nipple.
来了  熏牛肉加芥末  三号桌
All right, pastrami with mustard, table three.
二号桌的巨无霸三明治呢
w-where's the club sandwich for table two?
在这  爸
Right here, Dad.
我有个点子  老鲍勃
I got a great idea, Big Bob.
我来上菜
How about I run the food,
你就可以呆在厨房
that way you can stay in the kitchen
和小鲍勃一起下厨
and cook with Little Bob.
不不  我觉得老鲍勃上菜挺好  那
No, no, I-I think Big Bob is fine running the food. That's...
注意  二号桌
Look out, table two,
琳达给你上巨无霸三明治啦
here comes Linda with your club!
等等  二号桌是哪个
Wait, where's table two?
你点巨无霸了吗
You order a club?
巨无霸吗  巨无霸吗
Club? Club?
老爸的礼物
Present for Dad,
老爸的礼物  老爸的礼物
present for Dad, present for Dad.
好几罐豆酱
Cans of beans!
老爸喜欢在豆酱罐上打鼓  对吧
Dad loves to drum on beans, right?
这椅子怎么样  老爸偶尔也坐下来的
What about this chair? Dad sits sometimes.
没意思  等他死了有的坐  蒂娜
Boring. He'll sit when he's dead, Tina.
我们把这些捕鼠器都粘起来
What if we glue all these mousetraps together,
做个超级捕鼠器怎么样
and call it a super trap?
我把这椅子改成超级椅子如何
What if I make my chair a super chair?
比如说  我把这张纸贴上去
Like, if I tape this pad of paper to it,
他就能记日记了
then he could journal.
等等  等等  等等
Wait, wait, wait,
我们这是在比赛吗
Is this a little friendly competition we have here?
圣诞节的友谊比赛
A little Christmas competition?
谁给老爸最好的礼物  就能得到
Whoever gives Dad the best present, wins a...
一只槲寄生
A Mistle-Tony!
对  每个人最梦寐以求的奖品
Yes! The most coveted award in gift-giving!
我要带老妈去颁奖典礼
Dibs on bringing Mom to the ceremony!
-我带老爸  -我带老爸
- Dibs on bringing Dad. - Dibs on bringing Dad.
不行  你迟了一步
Nope, too late.
那你带谁  蒂娜
So, who you bringing, Tina?
我也不知道了
I don't know now.
好吧
Yeah.
烤架看着不错
So, uh, th-the grill seems good.
都快成老古董了吧
It's getting to be an antique.
我们都快了
Yeah, we all are, you know?
是啊
Yeah.
那是新的油烟罩吗
It-It's a new hood?
-买了五年了  -好用吗
- Five years ago. - Good hood?
挺好的  挺好的油烟罩
Yeah, pretty good. Pretty good hood.
我  我也有个挺好的
Yeah, I-I got a good hood, too.
那挺好的
That's good.
你总说你需要一个好的油烟罩
You always said you need a good hood.
我没说过
I never said that.
我记得你说过
I thought you said that; I... that's...
从没有人那样说过
No one in the history of time has ever said that.
"你只需要个好的油烟罩"
"All you need is a good hood."
我发誓我记得
I swear I remember
你说你只需要一个好的
you saying that all you need is a good...
那不是我  是别人
That wasn't me. It was someone else.
除了你  没人会那么说
I don't know why anyone else would say that.
老爸的椅子要完工了
Dad's chair is almost done.
他再也不需要站起来了
He'll never have to stand up again.
老爸要是渴了
Dad's thirsty.
这里有个水杯
He's got a water bottle.
他冷了
He's cold.
这有盒火柴
Box of matches.
他无聊了
Now he's bored.
也不必担心
Not anymore.
这有个篮球
Here's a basketball.
我还能用这张洗碗布
And then I can use this dish towel
和你们一起擦地板
to wipe the floor with you.
因为槲寄生我赢定了
Because I just won the Mistle-Tony.
你一看到这捕鼠器
when you see this trap,
就会闭嘴了
you're gonna want to shut yours.
句号  不伤你的心了
Period. End of burn.
你的礼物怎么样了  小鼓手吉恩
How's your present going, Little Drummer Gene?
豆子豆子  悲剧的果子么
Beans, beans, the tragical fruit?
关于豆子通气功效的美国童谣
"豆子豆子  神奇的果子  吃得越多  噗噗越多"
敲得越多  输得越惨
The more you drum it, the more you lose?
我是在说比赛  我们正在进行的那个
The contest? That we're in right now?
我改编了那首讲豆子的童谣
Like the saying, about the beans,
换了词儿
but with, uh, different words.
我本打算把这些罐子倒空
Well, I was gonna empty out these cans
这样鼓声更好听
to make a better drum sound,
但现在我想让这把老骨头
but now I think I might soak these old bones
泡个小豆子澡
in a little bean bath!
吉恩  你要退出比赛吗
Gene, you're pulling out of the competition?
不
No.
我只是午休会静静心
I'm just taking a little siesta to clear my mind.
蒂娜亲爱的  给我拿两片火腿
Tina, be a dear and get me two slices of ham
盖在我眼睛上吧
to put over my eyes?
爸  我大概还有30秒钟就要回去了
Hey, Dad, we're probably gonna head out in about, 30 seconds.
等做完这最后一单
So, just have to finish up this last order.
你看这上面写了什么
What do you think this says?
"烤奶酪"
"Grilled cheese."
烤奶酪
Grilled cheese.
-真奇怪  -什  什么
- That's weird. - Wh... what?
没  没事
Nah. Nothing.
算了
Never mind.
只是
It just...
上面写的"烤奶酪"
It says "Grilled cheese" on the ticket,
但我感觉你是在做"焦吐司"
but maybe you thought it said "Burnt toast,"
我也不知道
I don't know.
天哪
Oh, my God.
好了  爸  我们得上路了
Okay, Dad. We're gonna hit the road.
你们怎么样
How we doing?
挺好的  只是不知道为什么
Good. We're just learning how to make grilled cheese
我们还得从头学烤奶酪
for the first time, for some reason.
看呐
Oh, hey, look at me!
我接了个新单子
I got a new order over here!
柜台这的亨利说他想来份"老样子"
Henry here at the counter says he wants "The usual."
"老样子"
"The usual."
对啊
yeah?
我来负责亨利的老样子  鲍勃
I'll take care of Henry's usual, Bob.
你继续烤奶酪吧
You keep burning the grilled cheese.
不  爸  我来做这个
Oh, no, Dad, I'm gonna take care of this.
我来做亨利这份
I'm gonna take care of Henry.
你在说什么呢
What are you talking about?
我在说我14岁那年
I'm talking about the burger I tried
你让我负责餐厅
to make him when I was 14
我本打算给他做的汉堡
and you put me in charge of the restaurant.
就是说这个
That's what I'm talking about!
等等  什么汉堡
Wait, what burger?
"宝贝开我的车吧"汉堡  爸
The Baby You Can Chive My Car Burger, Pop!
好吧
Okay.
一切正常  大家聊天吧
Everyone's fine. Talking it out.
开始吧
Here we go!
我们来看看他有没有洋葱
Let's see if he's got any chives.
多半没有
Probably not!
他的餐厅怎么会有葱
Why would he have chives in a restaurant?
那样佐料就太多了
That would be too much flavor!
我有洋葱  伙计
Oh, I've got chives, buddy.
很好  准备好了吗  亨利
Good. You ready, Henry?
什么
What?
-你别管  亨利  -不好意思
- Stay out of this, Henry! - Sorry.
不准你在我的厨房里
You are not making one
做什么搞笑汉堡
of your gimmick burgers in my kitchen!
那是啥
What is that?
是车的声音
It's a car sound!
那才不是车的声音
That's not a car sound.
这才是车的声音
This is a car sound.
这才对
That's how you do it.
我滴亲娘啊
Oh, my God!
够了  别做了
All right, stop making that burguer right now!
亨利想要的是金枪鱼三明治
Henry wants the tuna melt!
-对吧  亨利  -不  老爸
- Isn't that right, Henry? - No, Pop.
亨利想要"宝贝开我的车吧"汉堡
Henry wants the Baby You Can Chive My Car Burger
就因为你他都没机会尝
he never had a chance to taste because of you!
那啥  我不想给你们添麻烦
Look, uh, I don't want to cause any trouble here.
你们上啥我就吃啥
I'll just eat whatever you put in front of me.
没关系  放轻松
No problem, easy breezy.
你会吃到金枪鱼三明治的
You're getting the tuna melt!
你会吃到我的汉堡的  亨利
You're getting the burger, Henry!
要是我先做好金枪鱼三明治那就别想了
Not if I make the tuna melt first!
祝你好运
Good luck!
喂  别挡着我
Hey, don't box me out.
如果你碰不到烤炉
Hey, if you're having a hard time
可别怪我
getting to the grill, it's not my problem.
抱抱
And... hug.
不抱吗  好吧
No? Okay.
老爸再也不用走路了
Dad will never walk again. By choice.
也再也不会
Nor will he love either of you again.
爱你俩了
By choice.
伙计们  你们听到我碎碎念了么
Guys? Did you hear my trash talking?
你伤不到我  蒂娜
You can't hurt me, Tina.
此时此刻  我是豆子  不是吉恩
At this point, I'm more bean than Gene.
都别说话
Nobody talk!
Nobody talk.
我只需要在这儿多放一块
I just need to get one more on here and...
我赢了  赢了  赢了
I win. I win. I win!
要是我已经完成了  那你还有可能赢
Oh, you might have won if I was done,
但我还没完呢
but I'm not.
在椅子背后贴一对电池
What could be better-y than a battery
岂不很妙
taped to the back of the chair?
我赢啦
Game. Set. Match.
不  不  不
No! No! No!
你高兴了吧  蒂娜
Hope you're happy, Tina.
现在老爸收不到圣诞节礼物了
Now Dad doesn't get a Christmas present.
那就给老爸这个
Looks like Dad just won a bean bath
有我嘘嘘在里面的豆酱浴缸吧
with a little pee in it!
那也不错了
Oh, that's something.
这会让老爸的皮肤看起来像回到四十岁
This'll make Dad's skin look 40 again...
不  我把豆酱撒了
No! I spilled my beans!
槲寄生看来是没戏了
I guess the Mistle-Tonys were a bust.
蒂娜  新比赛
Tina, new game.
你有十秒钟给老爸找个礼物  快去
You have ten seconds to find a gift for Dad. Go!
我们可以给他这个雪花球
We could give him this snow globe?
上面写着  "下雪啊  你没下"
It says, "Oh, snow, you didn't."
好样的  包起来  给它弄漂亮点
Attagirl. Wrap it up, make it look pretty.
我这儿有个又大又好看的蝴蝶结
I'd give you this big, beautiful bow,
不过要给你了我戴啥
but then what would I wear?
我把你的配菜扔了
I threw away your garnish!
该死
Damn it!
-上菜了  -上菜
- Order up! - Order up!
琳  把这端给亨利
Lin, take this to Henry!
不  琳达  那这端给亨利
No, Linda. Take this to Henry!
除非你两和好
I'm not taking anything anywhere
不然我哪份也不拿
until you two make peace!
知道你们需要什么吗
You know what you need?
来吧  各位  唱起来
Come on, people! Sing!
我们让这两个家伙和好如初
We can bring these guys back together!
*和气  和气  和气*
*Peace, peace, peace*
和气  和气  各位
Peace, peace... Everybody!
和气  和气  唱起来
Peace, peace...  Come on.
*和气  和气  和…*
*Peace, peace, pea...
快  和气
Yeah! Peace
得  我自己端给亨利
Fine, I'll take it to Henry myself!
我也是
Then I will, too!
把你的脚拿...
Get your foot out of my...
来嘛  今天可是圣诞节
Come on, it's Christmas!
给  亨利  老样子
Here you go, Henry. The usual.
给  亨利
Here you go, Henry.
"宝贝开我的车吧"汉堡
The "Baby You Can Chive My Car Burger."
*和气  和气*
*Peace, peace... *
好吧  不管用
All right, it's not working.
看起来都  不错
They both look... good?
-你这磨人的小妖精  -咬一口
- You son of a bitch. - Take a bite.
吃金枪鱼三明治  亨利
Eat the tuna melt, Henry.
我能  闻闻这个汉堡吗
Could I just give the burger, um, a sniff?
-亨利  -闻起来还不错
- Henry... - It's okay to smell.
-艾玛  -亨利
- Oy gevalt. - Henry...
很香  是吧
Smells good, right?
要不  就让我...
Maybe-maybe just a...
舔一口
A quick lick?
不  不准舔  别舔
No, not a lick. Don't do it.
别舔
Don't lick.
来吧  吃了它
Come on. Get it all
拿起来  亨利
Up in there, Henry.
别这么做  亨利
Don't do it, Henry.
算了  我还是不吃了
You know what? Maybe I won't.
我就知道你不会的  亨利
I knew you wouldn't do it, Henry.
天呐  我忍不了了
My God, I have to!
亨利
Henry!
咋了  我还没嚼呢
What? I'm not chewing.
我就在嘴里含一小会儿
I'm just holding it in my mouth for a second.
看到了吧  老爸
You see that, Pop?
对不起  不不
I'm sorry. Oh... Oh, no.
我吞下去了
I'm swallowing.
太好吃了
It's so good.
我再吃一口
I'm having another bite.
不
No!
我赢了
I win!
你现在得承认我的搞笑汉堡了吧  老爸
How do you like my joke burgers now, Pop?
好吧  小鲍
Okay, Junior.
你赢了
You win.
谢谢你来我的派对
Thanks for coming to my party.
各位  我全身都是豆酱哦
Hey, everybody! I'm covered in bean juice!
我跑  你们来抓我怎么样
How about I run around and you all try to catch me
就像抓在博览会上乱窜的猪一样
like a pig at the state fair?
我开始咯
Here I go.
来抓我呀
Try to catch me.
大家都不够努力哦
No one's trying very hard!
晚安  各位
Good night, everyone.
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas.
他出去了
Well, he's out.
各位又少了一个竞争对手
More bean boy for the rest of you.
老鲍勃汉堡店
咋了
What?!
都看着我做什么
Why is everybody looking at me?!
鲍鲍  冷静  冷静
Bobby, easy, easy.
-老爸  老爸  -咋了  露易丝
- Dad. Dad. - Yes, Louise?
貌似大家都在生你的气
Everyone looks like they're mad at you.
谢谢你哦
Thank you.
说不定这能让你开心起来  老爸
Maybe this will cheer you up, Dad.
谢谢  蒂娜
Thanks, Tina.
拆开看看  里面有东西
Open it. There's something inside.
雪花球
A snow globe.
-没错  -很棒  谢
- Yes. - Great. Th...
-等等  你们从哪拿的这个  -欧洲
- Wait, where'd you get this? - Europe.
不  我是说报纸
No, the newspaper.
你们在哪儿找到的
Where-where did you find this?
爷爷的地下室
From Pop Pop's basement.
-在他的书桌里  -看看他
- It was in his desk. - Look at him.
像小孩一样
He's like a baby,
还玩包装纸呢
playing with the wrapping paper.
鲍鲍  这是什么
Bobby, what is it?
这是开心汉堡店的第一篇报道
It's the first review of Bob's Burgers.
我爸把它保存起来了
My dad saved it.
天呐 好感人
Oh, my God. That's beautiful.
-快读一读  -算了吧
- Read it. - I don't think so.
读嘛
Read it.
-我不想读  -给我读
- I don't want to read it. - Read it!
"汉堡特别  价格公道
"Unique burgers. Good prices.
就是服务不太令人满意
"Service leaves something to be desired.
但还是值得一试的"
But worth the trip."
不怎么样嘛
Not great.
还行吧
I mean, it's okay.
鲍鲍
Oh, Bobby.
他是爱你的
He does love you,
但你却把他赶出了他自己的餐厅
and you drove him out of his own restaurant.
还是在圣诞节
On Christmas.
天呐
Oh, my God.
我做什么了
What did I do?
刚不是告诉你了嘛
I just told you.
-对哦  -在圣诞节把你父亲赶出...
- Oh. Right. - Drive your father out on Christmas...
好了好了  我听到了
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Yeah, I heard.
天呐  这也太悲情了
Oh, my God, that's so sad.
看来圣诞魔力也不管用了
So much for Christmas magic.
戴上这个  跟我走
Put this on and come with me.
等下  你说啥
Wait, what?
你老爸在我的酒吧里
Your dad's in my bar.
我带你去见他
We're gonna go see him.
-去吧  鲍鲍  -我  我...
- Go, Bobby. Go. - I-I...
我和孩子们会看好餐厅的  去吧
The kids and I will take care of the diner. Go.
是啊  老爸
Yeah, Dad.
当一个牛仔版圣诞老人召唤你时
When a mysterious cowboy/Santa says, "Come with me,"
你要做的就是跨上他的马背
you climb on that horse and ride.
再说了  还有免费的帽子戴呢
Also, free hat!
你开的不是舞厅吗
I thought this was a disco.
那是周三
That's Wednesdays.
周四我们一起看《丑闻》
Thursdays, we watch Scandal.
今晚是跳西部乡村舞蹈
Tonight's Country Western line dancing.
明天是圣诞
And tomorrow's Christmas...
你是不是已经忘了
or did you forget?
我知道  我知道
I know. I know.
当时我俩都太激动了
Things got a little heated.
他在那儿呢  去和他谈谈
There he is. Go talk to him.
别摘帽子
With the hat.
好吧
Okay.
让我自己待会儿
Just leave me alone.
-老爹  回餐厅来吧  -我忙着呢
- Pop, come back to the diner. - I'm busy.
你就只是坐在这儿啊
You're just sitting here.
才不是  我  我要去跳舞
No, I'm not. I'm... I'm dancing.
跳  跳舞
Da... dancing?
你又不会跳舞
You don't dance!
上吧  小鲍勃
Get out there, Bob Junior.
老爹  拜托回来跟我谈谈
Pop, will you please just come and talk to me?
要想跟你老爸说话
If you want to talk to your dad,
你就得和他一起"抖靴"
you're gonna have to boot scoot to him.
啥意思
What does that mean?
"抖靴"是啥
What's "Boot scoot"?
就像这样
It looks like this.
弯  弯膝
Bend... bend your knees.
我  我...  好吧
I'm-I'm... ow, okay.
扭臀
Now shake that pudding.
你想干嘛
What do you want?
我就想和你谈谈
I just want to talk to you.
你跳错了
You're doing it wrong.
舞步不是那样的
Those aren't the steps.
天  真的么
Oh, my God. Really?
所以我才不想和你共事
This is why I didn't want to work with you.
你老想控制我做的所有事
You have to control everything I do.
做菜  跳舞...
My cooking, my dancing...
并不是所有人都想跳得一样好吗
Not everyone wants to dance exactly the same way.
好吧  这示范不太好
Okay, bad example.
你们很擅长这个嘛
You guys are really good at this.
我每周五晚都来
I'm here every Friday night.
还有周四
And Thursdays.
我可爱看《丑闻》了
I love Scandal.
-老爹  难道..  -我不基  鲍勃
- Pop, are you...? - I'm not gay, Bob.
这些人是我朋友
These guys are my friends.
他们在我的餐厅吃东西
They eat at my diner;
我就过来跳舞
I come here and dance.
该死  又错了
Damn, missed it again.
你干嘛要过来  鲍勃
Why'd you come over here, Bob?
专门来跳错的吗
To miss steps?
听我说  老爹  你有你的脾性
Look, Pops, you are who you are,
现在我知道了  我该接受这个事实
and I realize now that I should just accept that.
好样的  做自己  姐妹儿
That's right. Be yourself, sister.
我只想说  我错了
I just wanted to say I'm sorry.
不为离开你
Not for leaving.
也不为自己开餐厅
And not for starting my own restaurant.
只为我们分手那天
But just for how I handled things on
我处理事情的方式
the day we broke up.
我知道那是你表达爱的方式  但...
I know it was your way of showing love, it's just...
我总觉得你从来都不支持我
I never felt like you were supportive of me.
至少在发现你保存的那篇报道前
At least, that's what I thought
我一直是这么想的
until I found the review you saved.
-你发现了  -孩子们发现的
- You found that, huh? - The kids did.
顺便说一句  让他们去你的地下室
Not a good idea to let my kids
可不是啥好主意
into your basement, by the way.
吉恩在那儿泡了个豆酱澡
Gene took a bean bath.
开来今晚还是有人过得开心的
Well, at least somebody's having a good time tonight.
老爸  对不起  我不该
Dad, I'm sorry. You didn't deserve
在你那么多顾客前让你难堪
to be embarrassed in front of your customers.
无论是今天  还是我小时候
I did it back then and I did it again tonight.
哈  又错了
Nope. Wrong time.
我知道你为什么离开
Listen, I know why you had to go.
我确实...不好相处
I can be... not great to work with.
你妈去世后我一直不好过
It was tough without your mom around.
你自己干得也很棒
You did great on your own.
-她会为你自豪的  -你真心觉得..
- She'd be very proud. - You really think...
好吧  就我自己面朝着这边
Okay, I'm the only guy facing this way now.
我还是转过来吧
So I'll turn around.
就这样
Here we go.
吉恩  把这碗清汤鸡肉面条端给五号桌
Gene, take this chicken noodle soup to table five.
好咧
On it!
蒂娜  去把厕所拖一下
Tina, clean up the spill by the bathroom.
我就是干这个的
Bathroom spill is my middle name.
乖孩子  露易丝  给柜台那边的
Attagirl. Louise, grab some napkins
小孩送点纸巾过去
for the kid at the counter.
-那小孩吃得满脸都是  -我知道
- That kid's a mess! - I know.
看看你的家人
Look at your family in there.
他们认真起来是能做得很好的
They really can sling hash when they want to.
他们平时可都不是这样的
They don't usually work this hard.
你有可爱的小孩
You got happy kids.
古怪又可爱的小孩  真好
Weird, happy kids. That's nice.
-你是个好父亲  -谢谢你  老爹
- You're a good dad, Junior. - Thanks, Pops.
我们进去吧
Let's go back inside, huh?
对  我们...
Yeah, let's...
-孩子们  让我们进去  -不要
- Kids, let us in. - No!
快开门
Open it!
这儿现在是我们的餐厅了
This is our restaurant now!
叫"宾至如归餐厅"
It's called Chez Restauranto,
经营巴西烤肉
and we're Brazilian barbecue!
我来开
Here.
-干嘛呢  蒂娜  -抱歉
- Come on, Tina! - Sorry.
好耶  圣诞魔力起作用了
All right! Christmas magic!
我的鲍鲍回来了
My Bobbies are back!
圣诞快乐  各位
Merry Christmas, everyone.
圣诞快乐  爷爷
Merry Christmas, Pop Pop!
*圣诞魔力*
*Christmas magic*
*年年来临*
*Comes every time each year, whoo!*
*圣诞魔力*
*Christmas magic*
*所有又冷又饿的人*
*And all the cold hungry people *
*圣诞魔力*
*Christmas magic*
*在大街上奄奄一息*
*They're dying in the streets *
这可不好
That can't be good.
*圣诞魔力*
*Christmas magic*
*而我们一家人今晚会暖洋洋的*
*Me and my family will be warm tonight*